fonearena.com 2005-05-06

# FoneArena.com - The Mobile Perspective>Specs,Price,News,Glossary,Forums

|  FoneArena privacy policy | 

**FoneArena Privacy Policy**  
  
---  
  
The following statement explains our policy regarding the personal information we collect about you **

1\. Statement of intent 

**  
From time to time, you will be asked to submit personal information about yourself (e.g. name and email address etc) in order to receive or use services on our website. Such services include newsletters, competitions, "Alert Email", live chats, message boards and FoneArena membership. 

By entering your details in the fields requested, you enable FoneArena and its service providers to provide you with the services you select. Whenever you provide such personal information, we will treat that information in accordance with this policy. Our services are designed to give you the information that you want to receive. FoneArena will act in accordance with current legislation and aim to meet current Internet best practice.   
  
**2.** **Information on visitors**

During the course of any visit to FoneArena, the pages you see, along with something called a cookie, are downloaded to your computer Most, if not all, websites do this, because cookies allow the website publisher to do useful things like find out whether the computer (and probably its user) has visited the site before. This is done on a repeat visit by checking to see, and finding, the cookie left there on the last visit. 

Any information that is supplied by cookies can help us to provide you with a better service and assists us to analyse the profile of our visitors. For example: if on a previous visit you went to, say, wallpapers, then we might find this out from your cookie and highlight wallpapers on a second visit.   
  
**3\. Use and storage of your personal information**

When you supply any personal information to FoneArena (e.g. for competitions, FoneArena Community services or FoneArena membership) we have legal obligations towards you in the way we deal with that data. We must collect the information fairly, that is, we must explain how we will use it and tell you if we want to pass the information on to anyone else. In general, any information you provide to FoneArena will only be used within FoneArena and by its service providers. It will never be supplied to anyone outside FoneArena without first obtaining your consent, unless we are obliged or permitted by law to disclose it. Also, if you post or send offensive or inappropriate content anywhere on or to FoneArena or otherwise engage in any disruptive behaviour on FoneArena, and FoneArena considers such behaviour to be serious and/or repeated, FoneArena can use whatever information that is available to it about you to stop such behaviour. This may include informing relevant third parties such as your employer, school or e-mail provider about the content and your behaviour. 

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as you use the service you have requested, and remove it in the event that the purpose has been met, or, in the case of you no longer wish to continue your status as a FoneArena member. For safety reasons, however, FoneArena may store messaging transcript data (including message content, member names, times and dates) arising from the use of FoneArena Community services for a period of six months. Where personal information is held for people who are not yet registered but have taken part in other FoneArena services (eg competitions), that information will be held only as long as necessary to ensure that the service is run smoothly. We will ensure that all personal information supplied is held securely, in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. 

If you are notified on FoneArena that your information may be used to allow FoneArena to contact you for "service administration purposes", this means that FoneArena may contact you for a number of purposes related to the service you have signed up for. For example, we may wish to provide you with password reminders or notify you that a particular service has been improved or suspended.
